

Pudongxin District, Shanghai, China

□ (+86) 131-6701-7220 | ► 77qingliu@gmail.com | 🏕 www.77qingliu.com | 🖸 77QingLiu | 🛅 77qingliu

"I believe a programmer's responsibility should not only be to produce TLF's from a set of specifications, but understand the therapeutic area, have a clear understanding of the key data points collected and the assumptions behind the statistical analyses done."

Summary_

3+ years' clinical trial working experience across Pharma, CRO, with solid projects hands-on experiences on oncology, autoimmune. Strong technical and problem-solving skills, open source enthusiasts and package/macro developer. Medicine, Statistics, Computer science compound background. Personal blog www.77gingliu.com, Github github.com/77OingLiu.

Professional Experience

Cowell Health - Hillhouse Capital Group

Shanghai, China

SENIOR BIG DATA ANALYST

Jun. 2018 - Present

- Mining, analyzing data from large pharmacy goods selling databases to generate sales reports and find insight through data analysis.
- Applying 'market basket analysis/association rules' on large amounts of transactional data(10B+) in company's big data platform for cross selling pharmacy products.
- · Scraping, cleaning, transforming drug, disease related data from various resources including CFDA, Encyclopedia and other websites.

Eli Lilly & Company Shanghai, China

STATISTICIAN - COMPUTATION Nov. 2016 - May. 2018

- Dedicated on phase I/III Oncology trials, routine work includes:
 - Provide significant input into statistical analysis plan development
 - Participate in SDTM/ADaM/TFL creation and corresponding specification development
 - Provide statistical support for TLSR, DSUR and IB, CSR, DMC, CTR etc
 - Communicate internally and externally on resource allocation, timeline negotiation, client expectation/feasibility evaluation, issue solving and share learning
- Lead an oncology phase I trial in Japan for PMDA submission, managing assignments to ensure deadlines are met and deliver portfolio milestones with speed & quality (TSLR, DSUR, TFL)
- Acted as leading statistical analyst, cooperated with HEOR team, analyzed the reliability and validity of disease measurement scale among
 Chinese populations. and Logistic regression analysis was used to analyze factors that influence the occurrence of the disease, published three
 papers/manuscripts, received LCDDMAC Excellence Award.
- Developed an innovative Python script for efficiently migrating many studies from SDD to Unix/SAS grid environment, automated the process of program modification, avoided tedious work and saved working time.
- Promoted version control of SAS programs using open source "Git" to manage project successfully.
- Hosted biweekly team meeting, develop a template to track project resource and workload, invite the local/global expert to share knowledge in working process and regulatory policy update.

PAREXEL Shanghai, China

STATISTICAL PROGRAMMER I & II

Jun. 2015 - Nov. 2016

- Worked with outsourcing projects from J&J company as a Statistical Programmer, involved in many clinical trials projects ranged from oncology and autoimmune therapeutic area, specific work includes SDTM/ADaM creation, TFL, and data verification listing development.
- Acted as leading Statistical Programmer responsible for oncology SDTM project, participated in eCRF review, annotate aCRF, SDTM Spec Writing and directing the programming activities of other programming personnel and monitors progress on programming deliverables.
- Developed a SAS Macro(AutoGenaCRF) for automatically generating aCRF, time in generating aCRF reduced from 2 weeks to 3 days.
- Promoted several innovative tools/macros(eg. Sublime Text) for internal efficiency enhancement.

Presentation & Publication

PharmaSUG China 2017 Shanghai, China

PRESENTER

Jul. 2017

Streamline Table Lookup by Embedding HASH in FCMP

Neuropsychiatric Disease and Treatment

Worldwide Jan. 2018

AUTHOR

 Reliability and validity of the Chinese version of questionnaire—Children with Difficulties for Chinese Children or Adolescents with Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder: a cross-sectional survey

AUGUST 21, 2018 77QINGLIU · RÉSUMÉ 1

Open Sourced Projects

AutoGenaCRF SAS Macros strove to automatically generate aCRF for FDA submission.

SAS-Syntax-and-Theme A SAS syntax highlighting package powered by regex in Sublime Text 3(download up to 5K)

Algorithms Data Structure/Algorithms implemented in Python

Honors & Awards.

LCDDMAC Excellence Award, Eli Lilly & Company Shanghai, China 2017 LCDDMAC Excellence Award, Eli Lilly & Company Shanghai, China Wuhan, China

2015 Outstanding Graduate, Huazhong University of Science and Technology

Education

HUST(Huazhong University of Science and Technology)

Wuhan, China

B.S. IN MEDICAL STATISTICS

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2015

• Core Curriculum: Health Statistics, Epidemiology, Multivariate Statistics

East China Normal University

Shanghai, China

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE CANDIDATE expected graduation 2020

77QINGLIU · RÉSUMÉ AUGUST 21, 2018